hello and welcome to the 13th tutorial
on how to program NG script 2 so in the
last tutorial I taught you about four
Loops well in this tutorial I'm going to
teach you about while
Loops so just type this and I'm going to
show you what they do while Loops are
very similar to four Loops except in the
parentheses they only have one parameter
like a four Loop would had three one two
three but a while loop only has
one and that one is if whatever is true
then run whatever is in the wild Loop so
let's do
this this dobat is equal
to one now in the wild Loop we
put if this dobo is less than 10 then it
will do whatever is in the W in the
parenthesis if it's not it's going to
just break the break the loop and Contin
onward so let's add here this dobo
equals this dobo plus plus so add it by
one oh I mean plus plus is what I meant
and we'll add this. chat is equal to
this. boo so we can see as the variable
changes then outside of the loop let's
add this. chat is equal to the loop
broke
and let's add a delay here so it doesn't
go too
quickly oh I mean sleep is what I
meant
sleep
0.1 so let's close it and
save so it's going to get to 10 then it
says Loop is
broken so that's pretty much what a
while loop is it's very similar to a
four Loop except it only has
one parameter manually I'm going to be
using four Loops so just know that so
right now I'm going to show you
something you can do with
loops okay so let's let's say we want to
animate this NPC to move this
way then go back to here and move back
this way again so it's sort of walking
to the
side well to that we would go here
actually
let's go and drag a new NPC
in a predefined one cuz we're too lazy
to add in it
ourselves whenever you're using gript
one you usually want to to make it
client side if you ever are going to be
using it let's down here let's add
function
on let's change this
to function fun on
created and here let's add function on
player
enters now what we're going to do is add
a for
Loop and add a variable called
temp. n zero then add
temp. n actually let's make it four
let's temp. n as long as it's less than
or equal
to 20 and over here let's add temp.
n equals temp. n +
0.2
now let's in the for Loop let's add
this.x is equal to temp.
n the x is is also a predefined variable
the x is what tile the NPC or players on
in the
level in the top in the top um in the
top left corner it would be 0 0 and the
bottom right corner it would be
6464 it's like as it as this the y- axis
goes down and the x-axis goes sideways
we'll go into more about that later but
just have a faint idea about it
so where is that okay here it is so the
NPC's X position is equal to temp. n at
first it's going to be four then it's
going to increase by
0.2 every
single 10th of a
second and once it gets 20 it'll break
the
loop so let's just close
this save it and upload you can see an
NPC that's the NPC and it's moving
sideways once the x value gets to 20
it'll stop there's 20 that means it's
gotten 20 tiles to the right from the
very edge of the level so that's it for
this tutorial we'll be adding a bit more
to our animated NPC later so anyway bye